The last man on Earth is not alone
I Am Legend is a drama, science fiction, thriller
film directed by Francis Lawrence.
Robert Neville is a scientist who was unable to stop the spread of
the terrible virus that was incurable and man-made.
Immune, Neville is now the last human survivor in what is
left of New York City and perhaps the world.
For three years, Neville has faithfully sent out daily radio messages,
desperate to find any other survivors who might be out there.
But he is not alone.
Robert Neville, played by Will Smith.
Anna Montez, played by Alice Braga.
Ethan, played by Charlie Tahan.
Alpha Male, played by Dash Mihok.
Zoe Neville, played by Salli Richardson-Whitfield.
Marley Neville, played by Willow Smith.
I Am Legend is a 2007 American post-apocalyptic action horror film directed by Francis Lawrence from
a screenplay by Akiva Goldsman and Mark Protosevich and starring Will Smith as U.S.
Army virologist Robert Neville.
Loosely based on the 1954 novel of the same name by Richard Matheson, the film is set in New York City after a virus, which was originally created
to cure cancer, has wiped out most of mankind, leaving Neville as the last human in New York City, other than nocturnal mutants.
Immune to the virus, Neville works to develop a cure while
defending himself against the hostile mutants.
It is the third feature-film adaptation of Matheson's novel following
1964's The Last Man on Earth and 1971's The Omega Man.
Warner Bros.
began developing I Am Legend in 1994, and various actors and directors were attached to the
project, though production was delayed due to budgetary concerns related to the script.
Production began in 2006 in New York City, filming mainly on location in the
city, including a $5 million scene at the Brooklyn Bridge.
I Am Legend was released on December 14, 2007, in the United States and Canada.
It opened to the largest-ever box office (not adjusted for
inflation) for a non-Christmas film released in the U.S.
in December, and was the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2007, earning $256 million
domestically and $329 million internationally for a total of $585 million.
The film received generally positive reviews, with Smith's performance being singled out for praise,
while criticism focused on its divergences from the novel, particularly the ending.
In 2022, a sequel was revealed to be in development, with Smith set to reprise
his role as Neville and co-produce the film with Michael B.
Jordan, who will also have a starring role.
The film explores themes of new york city, saving the world, based
on novel or book, dystopia, post-apocalyptic future.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.